Okay, so this evening we're going to talk about
ethical kink. Really, we should have done a call like this so much sooner.
When we said about doing this call, we were like, God, we should have training on
this, or we should have a call on this already.
I think so much of our training with regards to different niches covers a lot of
the stuff that we talk about here anyway, because obviously we're always thinking
about ethics and trying to do things in the right way.
But yeah, I'm really glad that we're going to have this call and hopefully an open
conversation about these types of things.
So, the ethical kink is what we're going to talk about today.
Do you want to do this first slide? Yeah, sure.
Hi, everyone. So ethical meaning. Living ethically is a commitment
to do no harm to yourself or others. Behaving ethically means doing your
best to obtain a good result for everyone with a stake in your actions.
So this is very important when holding a safe space for someone to explore their
kinks and fetishes. Okay, so
that is the meaning of ethical. That's what we're sort of aiming for.
We're aiming to commit to doing no harm, either to ourselves or to
someone else. And we're trying to get a good result for everyone with a stake in
our actions. Obviously, that's quite subjective, isn't it?
And probably ever changing. So in our commitment to ethical web camming, we
may make mistakes. We probably will when we make mistakes because we're human.
But with an intention to work respectfully, safely and with love, we're doing our
best to care for ourselves and our clients.
So in anything that we do, you know, whether it's like kink facilitation, obviously,
it's particularly important to think about ethics when you're doing something like
this. But in anything in life, you know, we can't be 100%
ethically, you know, we can't think about every single challenge
and every single choice and every single judgment we make.
We can't possibly know every consequence of our actions because, you know,
we don't have all that knowledge and we couldn't possibly, even with our best intentions,
avoid any negative outcome ever from anything we do.
So of course, you know, we're not aiming for perfection, but we are aiming to be
consistently being responsible for ourselves, being accountable, thinking
about why we're making the choices that we are and what impact they're having on
our clients. And particularly if we're working with kink, and if we get into a certain
niche, then we should take some time to upscale and to,
you know, expand our knowledge and make sure that we're acting,
you know, as ethically as we can be. So we're taking the best care of ourselves and
our clients, which of course is going to look different for different people and
for different kinks and on different days.
There's so much variation in acting ethically, which is one of the reasons for doing
this call to try and give you a bit of a bit of a framework or a bit of a, just to
open up the conversation about how to manage it.
So we can't always control all variables, and there may not always be great
options in terms of making choices, but we're just trying to get the best outcome
for everyone and trying to act ethically and look after ourselves and others.
So that's our intention to start off with.
Do you want to go through this, Jie? And the next slide, it kind of explains the
next bit, how to navigate these things. So the risk of harm.
If you're committing to an ethical way of living, either in kink facilitation or
in any area in life, that's important to understand.
Sorry, let me start that again a little bit, not really explain it properly.
Okay. So if you are committing to an ethical way of living, either in kink facilitation
or in any area of life, it is important to understand the potential risk
for harm. However... We cannot always predict or plan for every risk
of harm, so as Elle was just saying, we don't always know.
We can only remain committed to being aware and taking action where necessary.
So common risks of harm on cam are triggering someone,
discriminating against someone based on their race, class or gender, and also
taking someone beyond what is comfortable for them.
So there's some common risks of harm that could happen while you're on webcam, so
things that you need to be aware of to of course try and avoid.
So there are just some short sort of tips and starting points, and we'll go into
some of these things a little bit more, but for thinking about managing the risk
of harm for some of those risks that we've already mentioned.
So really important to try not to assume that you understand or that you know
someone's identity, that you know their limits, or even that you know their kink.
So even if someone comes into your room and you can see that they
have a certain name for example, or they've got a certain thing in their username,
which we would assume that they'd have a certain kink, it's okay to ask of course,
and to open up that dialogue and conversation, but never assume you're going to know
exactly what that client wants, because it’s you know assumption is just shutting
down curiosity, and we might get it wrong, we might say the wrong thing, we might
identify them in the wrong way, you know if they've got a certain sort of something
that alludes to a role play for example in their username, you don't know which
part of that role play that they want to play, just because they're like male presenting
or whatever, you don't know what their part in that story is just yet.
So not assuming straight away, just being open and listening and opening up the conversation,
which we all know are great things to do anyway because we're earning money while
we're doing this, so there's no harm in curious and just fleshing it out and getting
more information at first so that you can build on what they're saying rather than
just assuming you know what it is that they want.
So good questioning and communication before specific role play or kink ensures
you know what feels safe for them and what they want to get out of it.
So of course some people are going to come straight in and going to start straight
into something, but it actually I would say is quite unusual.
It's more common that they would start to tell you about the thing that they want
rather than jump straight into the thing that they want.
So there's already, they're already doing this sort of communication beforehand to
kind of like gauge you and to see whether this is going to be good for them, this
is going to be enjoyable for them. So yeah just being open and curious,
asking lots of questions, maybe making some suggestions and seeing how they react.
Of course you know like we said with the sort of acting ethically you can never plan
for every eventuality so you may see things you know that they don't respond well
to, but if you're open and curious and committed you know to be in that way then
it's okay you know because they feel safe to engage with you and to talk it through
with you. If something is going too far for you or
you feel the client is going too far for themselves, slow down and check in.
So check in either with yourself if for some reason you know usually and people have
different relationships with their bodies so of course it's not the same for everyone,
but usually you might you'll get a bit of a feeling of ease for some reason if you're
either going past the limit that you shouldn't be going past for yourself or if you're
feeling uncomfortable about the thing in terms of the other person if you're picking
up on something that's off with the other person.
You know so much about communication is not just what we're saying, it's the energy
behind what we're saying or the body language if you can see the person or whatever.
So trusting yourself and what you're noticing and what you're feeling and just slowing
down and checking in with yourself and with the client if it feels okay too is always
a good idea. So just noticing those changes in tone and when things getting a bit
odd or a bit much or just accelerated just you know feeling whether
that feels okay for you and whether you think that feels okay for them.
As we kind of If you're finding you're developing a
niche, it's so important, I think, to put, you know, it's like any job, isn't it?
You know, you're going to be good at your job if you've, you know, upskilled yourself,
if you've researched, if you've looked at, you know, for us, it can be quite enjoyable,
actually, that research, because you can look at different corners of the internet
and different role plays and, you know, learn about how other people are doing it,
get inspiration from them. We've got a huge training library, of course, with so
many different things that you can learn about all different types of kink.
And there's so much online now about kink and about safe kink that, yeah,
if you find that the same sort of clients are coming back to you, or you're doing
the same thing over and over, or you're interested in it, then just spend some time,
even maybe while you're waiting for calls, just googling it and finding out about
things. And sometimes that's great, because it gives you inspiration for things that
you can ask clients about. If you don't know about, if you don't know a lot about
certain kink, and then you, you go up and Google it and read a load about it, you
can be like, Oh, yeah, well, this is one aspect of it, maybe I can ask them if they
like that sort of thing. So it's all feeding into acting
ethically, but also just giving you like inspiration for things to say to your clients
as well. So it's a win win, really. And remembering that consent
is about autonomy. So which means kink play is
only safe when it involves choice, and there's an option to change your mind.
So consent is about autonomy, which means consent is about choice.
It's about having the choice to do something and being able to remove that choice
or change that idea at any time. So that that is relevant for you, as
the facilitator, someone who's holding this space with clients, and it's also true
for them. So in order for them to be safe, they need to know that they can stop or
slow down or whatever at any time. And obviously, because we're online, we're so
much safer anyway, because if they, you know, if the person you're speaking with
gets to a point where they've changed their mind, or they're feeling something or
whatever, they can just leave the call. So it's not like we're doing, you know, in
person things where we really have to make sure that we're tuned in because their
safety is completely in our hands. So we can sort of take that weight off ourselves
a little bit. And but it's still important to remember that that it's always about
choice and consent is always about choice.
And I'm hoping I'm not going to have to adjust.
I think my wire might be loose on my ring light.
This is why I'm flashing now and again. I can go through this slide if you want to
sort that out. And then yeah, you do that.
Make sure my consent. So consent is the permission for something to
happen, or an agreement to do something. And yeah, if they do this, we
can ask the clients for a safe word as well to really know that we've always got
consent. So as I was saying previously, and maybe some of the kinks that
they're into, or what they're telling you they like, maybe they'll change their mind
at some stage. And that's okay. And at least if they have a safe word, if we've already
established a safe word, then when they do change their mind, or when it does get
to a stage where they're not comfortable anymore, they can use their safe word.
And then you'll know to take it in a different direction, or just stop what you're
doing completely and regroup and just speak about things again.
And, and the picture also how it says you need more than a safe word, you need clear
communication about what is and isn't acceptable before you even start.
So that's what we also mentioned previously on this call is to just really have a
conversation about, you know, what they like, what they don't like, what, what's
acceptable, what isn't. And then of course, always have the safe word.
And then you fully covered yourself and your clients.
And yeah, and then you can play with the roleplay or whatever it is you're doing.
And know that if it does start to go too far for either one of you, you can use the
safe word. And so yeah, now we'll take a look at a few different models of
consent. And I was just gonna come to the question.
So the question in the chat, Maria, Maria, thank you for the question.
And so sometimes clients are drinking, especially on a Friday night, and they can
sound coherent, but how consensual is that?
And obviously, they are eager to spend, but to me, it's an ethical dilemma.
Yeah, that's a really good question. That's a really good question.
I think that, of course, it's always going to be a judgement, but it's going to be
an ethical dilemma. That you make, isn't it?
So You can't always make a perfect judgment, and you're not
always going to know completely what's going on for them and what's normal for them
in terms of drinking or whatever else. The
different models of consent that we're going to look at now can act as a bit of a
guide. If you get to a point where, like the example you're given, you've got a bit
of an ethical dilemma and you don't know, then that's what these models are for.
To give you just something that you can quickly refer to when you're making that
decision, because it is your decision at the end of the day, you know, it's you that's
making that call. So let's have a look at those.
You're welcome. So
these are, and there are honestly, there are so many, there are so many different
models of consent, which is great. Like we should all be talking about consent in
different areas of life, but these are particularly for kink and BDSM.
So they're basically different acronyms that have, you know, come up over the years.
Some of them are a bit outdated now, but you know, a different one might work for
you than somebody else. So if one of these kind of sticks in your mind and helps
you, then I think it's good to just go over a few and give people choices.
So SSC is like a really old one, which I think is
questionable, obviously, as a therapist. This one stands for safe, sane
and consensual. I don't really like the language in that because I don't know how
we objectively figure out what's sane and what's not in terms of kink and fetishes.
But, you know, if that, you know, if you
relate to that and you can use that, then, you know, it's one way of trying to establish
whether you think something is consensual.
So yeah, it's the oldest model of consent in the BDSM community.
A bit outdated now for many reasons, but that's kind of a starting point where we
started from. So RAC then at the bottom left is
another acronym for consent, another model of consent, and it means risk aware, consensual
kink. I like this one because I think it's, as it says,
it's more a bit more specific. So if you're thinking about safe, sane and consensual,
like how do you judge what is safe, sane and consensual really?
But I think RAC, risk aware consensual kink, means that you're
aware of the risk and you're factoring that into whether or not you think that this
is a consensual act. So like the example that was just given, one of the risks is
that the person is under the influence of something.
So, you know, might not have the ability to consent, you know, at some point.
So in order to act ethically, you'd be just continually monitoring that risk.
And, you know, if it gets to a point where you're feeling uncomfortable or you think
this is not safe for the other person, then you'd be winding down and ending that
call. There's also PRIC, maybe
an easier one to remember, the word, stands for personal responsibility informed
consensual kink. So it says this model began to gain popularity in 2009.
You know, all models of consent really are about personal responsibility because
we're responsible for the other person and for ourselves.
But it's just reminding you of that, you know, that it's your responsibility to manage
the risk. And then lastly, which is one that I
really like as well, is the four Cs, which is caring, communication,
consent and caution. And it says there that it's used in 24-7 power dynamics,
which means that it's used more in dynamics where you have
a power dynamic, say a sub, a dom sub, that is 24-7 your dom sub.
So you've got a living person or an ongoing arrangement where you're, you know, you're
always in the same role. And in those cases, I
mean, it's quite rare that we're going to have that on cam.
But we may do, we may do, we may after the initial like contracting and figuring
out what's going on and talking and chatting, we may, you know, have a sub.
For instance, that every time they come on cam, they are our sub and we don't step
out of that role, at least very often at all, which would be close to a 24
seven power dynamic. So in those instances, the four C's is really good because it
just makes sure that you're, it's basically a set of principles or a set of values,
and as a framework for consent. So everything you're doing is caring, you're
communicating properly, you're making sure that you've got the consent, and you're
using caution, you're exercising caution.
Especially when, you know, there are some circumstances that might make it hard for
the other person to withdraw their consent.
So for example, if they're doing, if they're doing something on cam, and they're
facing the other way, or whatever, you know, it might not be as easy for you to hear
them withdraw their consent or say a safe word or something.
So in those instances you're acting with caution, you're being really cautious and
putting things in place to make sure that they can still stop whenever they want
to, for instance, raise your hand instead of speaking out if you're over there, or
something like that, you know. But yeah, these are some of the different models of
consent, I think it's good if you can just pick one of those, you can Google them,
there are others as well. But just to have it like maybe written down on a little
post it or something. I mean, I think it's good, even not just in terms
of like kink, but just in terms of life and relationships, you know, to have those
values is kind of what is why we are the ethical community because we try to have
those values and everything we do, of course, you know, maybe we can't always be
perfect, we certainly try to be as close to that as we can.
So yeah, being caring, communicating, prioritising consent and being cautious.
And hopefully that answered that question a little bit, that previous question.
Do you want to do this one? I love this picture, by the way, so cool, isn't it?
Yeah, that's a nice photo. So practise tuning into your own and your
client's body language and inner experience.
So be curious and learn to trust yourself.
So we touched on this earlier about the body language.
So obviously, that's also an indicator of how someone's feeling.
And then also for ourselves as well. So, you know, obviously, we want to make sure
we're holding our clients in a safe, like ethical space.
But we also want to make sure we're doing that for ourselves.
And we're never doing anything that we start to feel uncomfortable about too.
And so always take a minute to check in with yourself, see how you're feeling about,
you know, where the conversation is going and where this call is going.
And then, of course, always make sure you're checking in with your clients.
And it might be harder, you know, to see the body language on cam, especially if
you can't see them at all. But if you can see them and you've got a relationship
with them, you'll start to know, you know, you'll start to see certain signs about
their body language and if you think they're enjoying it or not through their body
language. And then you can always ask and just, yeah, make sure that they're,
you know, doing okay throughout the call.
But yeah, at the end there says about being curious and learning to trust yourself.
I think that if you are acting from an ethical place, then you definitely can trust
that you're doing things right and doing it, you know, with a good heart
and in it from a good place. And obviously, you still need to check in.
But as long as you're doing the framework that we looked at previously, and you know,
making sure we're being caring and cautious and all of these things, then we can
definitely trust ourselves that what we're doing is right.
Yeah, I think that's such a good point that like, that, you know, following
one of those frameworks, that's what builds your body's trust with you.
Like, so, you know, it's, it's both of those things together, isn't it?
It's like the logical having a framework in your mind, but also your body, what your
body's doing or saying is also like those two things hand in hand over time, you
might not have it straight away. But like, any sort of trust is earned and built.
So learning to trust yourself and make decisions based on those frameworks over time
is going to help you to feel better, you know, and more confident as well when you're
online. And, and I just put
a little point about like, maybe some things you might only feel comfortable to do
if you're doing cam to cam. So if you can actually see the person that you're doing
some web facilitation with, I mean different people might have different ideas about
this and that's okay. But personally there are probably some things that I would
only do if I can see the person, because I like to be able to tune in and actually
see and watch them and sort of make sure I'm holding that space by seeing them as
well. So maybe there are different things that you might do with when you can see
the person as to when you can't. And I
think when we say like tuning into your own body, I think that maybe
a lot of people can get a bit freaked out if they get like, if your stomach turns
or you feel a bit of anxiety or you've got a flutter or something happens.
But I think it's learning, and of course everyone's different, we've got our own
histories and our own lives to respond to.
But it's learning that those things are not necessarily a warning, sometimes they're
just a communication from your body. You know, so like just learning to just look
inward for a moment and just be curious about what that communication is.
It could be that you like the thing, you know, it could be that it reminds you of
something else, it's getting close to your own experience which doesn't feel good
or feels okay and might actually be a bit healing and you can continue with it.
So yeah, those like sensations or whatever from your body, not assuming straight
away that you know that what that is either, just waiting for a minute and being
curious and like, okay, yeah, I feel okay to continue or no actually.
And sometimes, even if you check in with yourself, because you feel a bit of anxiety
or whatever and then you're like, no, no, I'm going to continue.
Sometimes it's okay to just be like, no, actually, I'm not going to, I'm just going
to step out of this one because again, your body needs to learn to trust you.
So sometimes it's okay just to say no, even if you're not sure.
It actually is, I always recommend this in terms of like, in a different sphere in
terms of like doing kink in person, it's always good to exercise your right to consent,
even if you're, you know, kind of thinking or maybe it's okay, just now and again
or even once, just so that your body knows that you can say no, to build that trust
with it. And so yeah, quite a lot there about tuning into your body.
And then I was going to talk just a little bit about framing roleplay
and kink. So we've kind of talked about it a bit already.
I think it's good to like hone in on this because, especially in webcam, like
the beauty of webcam is that we can frame a session that
we're doing, which means it will have a time boundary, which is good for autonomy,
because it means that the person knows exactly a bit more what's going to happen.
Okay, we're gonna do this for this set of time, or we'll chat for the first 10 minutes,
and then we'll get into the session. And I think, like, George has often said on
other calls, like sometimes like with a sub client, you're like even or maybe
look away or like go out of the room and come back in, like, have something that
represents that time boundary. Like, first we're chatting and, you know, figuring
it out, and then we're actually in it. Is that right, Jay?
You do that sometimes? Yeah, definitely. You can like, even go off the camera, and
then come back in that like dom role or like even go off, put something new on maybe
an outfit that's going to help you step into that role, you know.
So like, yeah, so they know the first part is the conversation where you talk about
the limits, talk about what's, you know, what's okay and what's not, talk about the
safe word, find out what they're into. And then you come away, come back, and
that's when you're in your dom role. And then there's not so many questions, it's
more you guiding the session, because you've already asked all the questions and
you've already found out what they're into and what they're not, what is safe and
what isn't. But then, of course, throughout the session, you will use some of the
frameworks that we spoke about just to make sure that, you know, you're still taking
it in the right direction, like you don't just assume, just because they told you
10 minutes ago they're into this. And then when you do it, maybe you'll start to
see they're actually not into it so much and they're not really enjoying it.
So yeah, just always obviously staying curious throughout the session as well.
But yeah, that's how I like to do it. And that's just an example of what I mean when
I say framing, because what G is doing there is like, almost having
an intro and a nice little chat, which is like some of these things, it's like good
communication, it's building... Your relationship, it's like preparing for the session,
and then you're doing the thing that you're doing.
And then maybe afterwards, you might have a little like, oh, yeah, that was really
good, or like, what did I like or ending the session in some way.
So you framed it by having something either side, basically.
And like Gee says, you know, knowing the limits.
So at the start, when you're doing that framing, when you're having that conversation,
looking at the keywords, so having a safe word, it can be good.
I mean, I like to have a safe word and an amber word, which a safe word
means stop on the amber word means slow down, or check in.
And so you don't necessarily have to stop, you know, you don't have to go straight
to a stop, it can be just like a slow down, tune in, you know, like, this is going
a bit quick, or I'm not sure about this. So pull back.
And so yeah, so framing it is really, I think it's a really great thing to do.
Obviously, sometimes, you know, calls are a bit more casual, and it's not like an
ongoing client kink client that you've got.
So you just, you know, it might be a Friday night, and they just go back and forth
with you about a fantasy they've got or whatever, in which case, you know, might
not be necessary. But if you know, you know, that the client is really into something,
and it's a specific niche or a specific roleplay, sometimes they can feel
so much safer, and more excited by the fact that you're framing it in this way, because
you're making more of a deal of it, it's more of a thing, you know, especially if
you're going off and getting changed and coming back.
I mean, that is like exhilarating in itself, isn't it?
And doing, having those types of relationships where you're framing it, it really
helps you build a relationship and get good ongoing relationships with clients that
will keep coming back to you, because they feel, you know, in the middle bit of the
session, they might want to be degraded and on all sorts of things, but either end
of that, they feel respected and safe and listened to.
And just that contrast can be so amazing.
It's like magic, isn't it, for some clients when they can hand over their self to
you, because they know that they trust you and respect them, and then you can do
some really harsh stuff, and then at the end they can come back and feel held and
safe and respected again. You know, that is what makes kink, in my opinion anyway,
that's part of what makes kink, you know, transformative and special, is that you
have a relationship like that. And I've personally had some like beautiful relationships
with like people who have been a sub online, who have, you know, in the framing,
either side of what we've been doing. I've been asking them like, well how, what
got you into this? And they've like talked about their memories, and of course we're
getting paid for these conversations, but they're just lovely conversations where
you're just connecting with someone, and you're finding out about why they got into
this thing, and then next time they come back, you can maybe say, well maybe we can
take it down this way, considering what you told me, you know, before.
And that can be really fun, you know, just give you more ideas.
So, so yeah, framing role-playing Kink is a really good thing to think about, and
yeah, just the last point, and that was about ending and reviewing.
So of course, like at the end of a call, I mean of course some people are going to
run off or whatever, but if you do have that framing, and you can ask them about
it, you know, and being open to feedback as well, like which parts did you like?
Was there anything that you weren't sure about, like what would you like to do more
of? Such a great way to end a call, like a kink call, because they know that they've
been listened to, and there's also room for more next time, so it's like okay, maybe
next time we can do this or that or whatever.
So that's framing. Yeah, I
think so. So is this okay to have fantasies and or kinks that
you won't engage with, but it's not okay to shame others about their kinks?
If you're unsure or worried or need support, please contact your mentor or one of
the team. So yeah, so we definitely aren't here to kink shame anyone, that's for
sure, but that's the same, you know, on the flip side, we definitely don't want to
be doing any kinks or exploring any kinks with clients that we don't want to, and
that's absolutely okay. We can just tell them, I'm sorry, I don't offer that.
You can find that with somebody else on the website and just wish them a good day.
You don't have to make them feel bad about it.
You don't have to shame them. You can just say, You can even say, you know, I don't
facilitate that, I don't know enough on that subject, or you know, that's not part
of my repertoire, whatever it is you want to say, but just say it in a way that's
not going to shame them because we don't want to be here to do that.
But definitely do let them go if it is something that you don't want to offer.
Don't push your own boundaries. But yeah, that's what I would say on that one.
Yeah, and obviously you can post in the group.
I mean, people have done this a lot, like if there's something you're unsure of,
speak to your mentor or one of us, like usually you can get hold of one of us quite
quickly. And just check in with someone, even if like you've already made the decision
and you've already done the thing or whatever.
Sometimes you just need to talk about it, don't you?
Or just like a bit of a debrief or whatever.
So it's okay to do that. And it's also okay, like, you know, to
on the point of having things you don't engage with, it's okay if those things change
over time. Or even not even over time with different people, like,
you know, I might be okay to do a certain thing.
But then if someone comes into the room and just the energy's off, I'm just not going
to do it because I just, there doesn't need to be a reason, does there, back in my
body's telling me that I don't want to do that.
So it's totally okay to do that. And yeah, and over time, you
know, I know for myself, I've been curious about things over time that maybe I would
have said no to in the beginning, or gone through phases where I'm doing something
in my own life, and I'm like, I'm not going to do that thing anymore.
And I think if there's something that you're just a bit icky about, I
think just listen to that. And don't push yourself, because it doesn't
mean that you're shaming someone else. If you're not doing it, that doesn't mean
that like, and I think one one really icky thing that
particularly comes to mind is the one that I've had a lot of people message me about.
It's like race play, something that I've never ever done.
And I just, oh, it makes me feel like so icky just thinking about it.
But I think that's, that's one sort of thing.
And things are similar to that, where if you're not from a minority, and someone
from a minority is asking you to do this, it can be, it can easily be like, Oh, okay,
well, I want to I want to facilitate or I want to help this person who wants to do
the thing, because they're asking me to do the thing.
But if it doesn't feel okay for you, it doesn't matter.
Doesn't matter what the other person wants in that moment, it's okay to say no.
And try and think if there's anything else important to mention on this, but I
think maybe, maybe that's okay. And does anybody
want to either share, like, something that they've been thinking about or how they've
something that's come up for them in this or ask a question?
Anybody have anything else they'd like to talk about?
No more questions? I
have a question. Yeah, sure. Yeah, thank you.
So for me, a race-based humiliation is really challenging.
Although like, I'm thinking, okay, how is it different, for example, from small penis
humiliation, which is basically like body shaming.
But, like engaging with racism is difficult, although like, it's really, some
clients really want me to do that. So do you do that?
And how do you explain it to yourself? Yeah, I
think if you're having to explain something to yourself, then my opinion is not
to do it. Because if you're having to sort of find a way to do something that doesn't
feel good for you, there's a reason why it doesn't feel good for you, you know?
What would you say, Georgia? Yeah, exactly the same.
I've had clients over the years also asked me to do like racial domination or like
degradation or humiliation. I don't do any of that racial stuff.
I'll do like small penis humiliation or stuff like that.
I feel better about that. And maybe some people wouldn't, they even still would think,
like you said, it's body shaming, and it's not nice.
But for me, that doesn't feel, it doesn't feel as heavy as...
Racial humiliation, so I've always said no to that, because I've just always known
I would never feel okay about that. And I've just sent them elsewhere, I've just
said, look, I don't know enough on this to offer this to you, please find someone
else to do this. And they should listen if you're their master, you can send them
somewhere else to go get it from another mistress or another goddess or whatever,
you can have them get that from somebody else and then come back to you.
So they should listen to you anyway if you're their dom.
So if it already doesn't feel right to you before you've even done it and you have
to explain to yourself how you're going to do it and try and make yourself feel okay
with it, then like Elle said, you definitely shouldn't do it because it already doesn't
feel okay before you've even done it. And I know that maybe you'll think, oh, you
know, there's clients that you're missing out on because of this, but there's so
many more clients out there that want things that you will offer.
And it's not going to make you feel bad about offering those things either, you know,
like only offer what you feel comfortable to offer.
Don't do something that at a later date, you might look back and think, oh, I wish
I didn't do that, I wish I didn't say that, you know, because you've got to live
with that, you know what I mean? Maybe no one else is ever going to find out and
it's never going to come about that, you know, you've had this racial play like conversation,
but you would know yourself that you've done something that hasn't felt right to
you. So I would just say no, that's what I would do if it already didn't feel good.
Yeah, thank you. Because yes, somehow like smoking is humiliation.
And as you were saying before, like very often, the addicts are not even like small.
And it's kind of like, it's really, I don't know, it's really like fun and light,
but like race sounds, I don't know, to me very heavy.
And I have one more question. So, you know, that I did all the training, like before
starting, and very often I find that clients just actually want to jump into the
sessions very, very rarely, they want to like have some aftercare, very often they
just jump, jump out. And even when I start kind of like talking to them about like
all this like safe word and everything, they're kind of like, they want to jump into
the session straight away. I guess, I don't know, maybe it's like how just the
money aspect of camming or like the online nature
of it is changing the whole with this scene setting.
So it's very rarely that they actually are open like to have this like nice long
conversation. Very often they're just saying, okay, I want, I want this.
I want small things, humiliation, just, and I'm asking them about some details,
but sometimes they even leave when I'm asking them about details because yeah, it
feels like they just want to straight away.
So how to balance between like this, like immediate needs, which are, I guess, becoming
more and more transactional rather than relational and the
desire to actually like do things ethically and properly.
Yeah. Okay. Well, in that, in that type of call, I would just say, look, we
don't need to spend too much time going through things.
I already know that you're into small penis humiliation.
I can offer you that. But what I do need before we start the session is a safe word
or safe words and amber words or just safe words, but at least, you know, at least
a safe word at least. So then, then, you know, you know, at least you've set something
in place and that doesn't take, that takes a moment just to set a safe word, you
know? So you could say, I would prefer to speak more about what you're into
so I can get a proper idea of, to give you the best session possible.
But if you want to rush into it, we can head into the session in a moment, but I
just need this and this from you. So then at least you're getting one or two things
from them. You're not just rushing straight in without even a safe word, you know?
So I would do that. I would just get the basics, like the bare minimum, and then
you can do the session. And then maybe then they'll start to think actually, you
know, and then at the end of the session, you can be like, look, when we meet again,
let's spend a little bit longer in the next time in the beginning, just really establishing
exactly what you're into, where you would like the session to go, because we want
this to be safe and enjoyable for the both of us, and we want this to be as enjoyable
as possible. So the more I know about what you're into and your desires and your
fetishes, your limits, the more I know about all of this, the better experience I
can give to you. So that's how I would play that one, but I would at least set up
a session. It's really important that you have a safe word, no matter what, no matter
how fast they want to be. You can just establish the safe words, you know, that takes
a second. So that's why I would say that.
But yeah, it's like you said, it's like sometimes they just want it fast and it's
like, it kind of then takes away from what we're actually here for on the experience
they can have. But then, you know, maybe like you said, maybe it's because they don't
have enough money to be able to spend that long in the first part and the last part.
So just make it a bit shorter. But yes, some of them really will, like Elle said,
they will love the fact that you spend time in the beginning and the end.
Like, proper subs will love that. But then some others, yeah, they'll just want to
rush in. So it's just trying to find that balance, I suppose.
I think in the middle of those two groups as well, because there's, so there's different
types of clients, right? There's the serious kink clients who want that because they
like the framing because they know more and they're into it properly.
And then there's like the people who just come home from the pub and like, you know,
thought they had a small dick once, so they just want to keep, they just keep doing
that thing, but they're just not, they don't really understand it or want to understand
it. They're just a bit pissed and they want to, you know, it's just coming up for
them in that moment. So, and there's probably, there's all the spectrum in between,
of course. So yeah, so there's, I think, yeah, what G said is really good, like trying
to get the bare minimum. But also, I would say like some clients, you can do a bit
of it without them knowing what you're doing necessarily, as in like, you can ask
them questions or make the questions part of the dynamic that they want to experience.
So they want to be humiliated. So making it like, oh, well, you don't, you don't
even know what you're doing here, do you?
So you don't want a safe word, so you don't, you know, like stepping into control,
you can even do that as part of the setting up of the process.
It's just giving them the dynamic that they want straight away, but still getting
what you need out of it kind of thing, you know.
Yeah, thank you. Can I have just one last question?
I'll stop. So sometimes they are saying that, for example, their wife
is sleeping next to them and they want to kind of like do something, and
then like this for me really triggering because I think of that like case when like
the woman was raped by many, by many men in France.
Like when there is a person like who is unaware and this kind of like participate
in the scene. So I think like I'm normally like saying, can
I have her consent? And then they disappear.
So what do you think about that? Like, overall, when they are saying that, like,
they're not sure if this is like true, because sometimes they're saying, would you
like to come to come with me with my wife like sleeping next to me?
Like, only if I have her consent. So, yeah, well, they are actually
not allowed to do that. You're not allowed to have somebody in the back of your cam.
I mean, you can get your profile shut down for having someone else in the back of
your cam. So that's, that's not allowed. And I think some of the time it can be,
they're just saying it, they're just saying that someone's in the next room because
they like the thrill of that. Again, I would say anything that you're not comfortable
with and doesn't fit in with one of those frameworks, if you don't feel that it's
like, if it hits all those things and you feel uncomfortable with it, then don't
do it. You know, it's completely up to you what you feel is ethical and consensual
for you. So, you know, is there anything you'd add to that, G?
Yeah, definitely. Because it leads into a question that Ivy's actually just asked
in the chat. They said, will we lose clients if we get triggered by
a client request and they will leave the call?
Will this impact our business and are there many new clients on the site?
So this kind of leads into what we're saying here.
Yes, there are many new clients on the site.
And yes, people will believe if you don't, you know, if you're not facilitating what
they want, and that's absolutely fine. You know, if you try to hang on to every single
client that came into your room and offer them what they want, even if you don't
want to do it, you're not going to last long in there because you'll start to get
a really bad feeling about webcam. And this is why since the beginning, we've always
like stressed to live within your boundaries and only do what you're comfortable
with. Because trust me, there are many clients on there.
And yeah, you know, you might have to turn 10 clients away before you get one that's
going to stick. And that's going to be a regular who spends a lot of money on you.
So don't be afraid. I'm afraid to turn them away.
I know it's like paying clients and it's money that you're turning away, but you're
feeling and what feels good to you is more important.
And you will still make the money, you will still make it with somebody else who
is doing something that you want, that you like, and you can have a nice back and
forth with them. So yes, we've always said that, just say no, don't do it,
and someone else will come, 100% they will.
We don't want anyone ever doing something that makes them feel not good about themselves,
because no amount of money is worth that.
There's so many more clients, trust me. Yes, one did some clients for us all.
And I think sometimes you, without even doing anything triggering, I've, especially
in the early days, just spoke to people for longer than I wanted to speak to them,
just because I'm trying to get money. Like I think there's, obviously there's a line,
it's like where you decide the line is, isn't it?
Like I probably, I may, in the early days, I probably quite a lot, like pushed myself
to keep talking to someone that was boring the hell out of me, or just like their
energy was just like, oh. But I felt like that was okay because I needed the money
and I felt okay with doing that and it didn't make me feel bad afterwards, once the
call was finished, that was it. But I think that's where my line is, like if I put
this call down and there's any residual bad energy from this, like if it's going
to stay with me in any way, that's a no from me.
You know, if it's okay, if it's like, Mark, this person's boring the hell out of
me and he's bloody patriarchal bullshit or whatever, I can sit with that for a little
bit because I'm draining his money. And afterwards I'll feel fine about it, but I
think, you know, if it's something that I'm going to actually do, or that's just
going to make me give you the ick, then I just think it's not worth it, is it?
There will be other people come in. And it's hard when you're, it's hard when you're,
you know, there's like a conversation in there about privilege as well.
Like it's hard when you're depending on some money and you're like sat there.
And of course, you know, every client is, could be money, but I think it's just about
balancing what is important to you in that moment.
Like, yeah, because it's holding your boundaries online is I think it's even more
important in person because it takes more to tune into yourself.
And it's easier. Maybe it would be easier to go past your boundaries.
But it's not worth it in the long run. And I was thinking as well
about the question about like race play and I think, I think, with things like that
it's important to mention about like marginalised groups,
like about oppression. Like for me, part of being ethical, either in
kink or in life, is understanding, you know, systems of oppression.
It's understanding that, you know, a white woman has a privilege over a black woman
or whatever, you know. So I think it's important to hold, to do a bit of research
and to understand like if there's privilege that you're holding, or if there's, you
know, privilege that the other person that you speak to is holding over you.
I think that that's an important part of managing like what you're doing and how
you're speaking and, you know, whether you're being ethical or not, because we have
a whole history that's informing us and our bodies, you know, even if we don't know
it. So, yeah, for me, part of being ethical is also taking into account all those
things, which I can't always do all the time, of course, because we're human, you
know, we can't be perfect in it, but we can try, we can try our best.
So, yeah. And also one thing I actually I was thinking when you were saying about
that some clients just want to be quick and whatever, of course, there's always going
to be those. But I think that the way that your profile sounds, the way it's written,
what is on there will also reflect the type of clients that you get.
So I think that for me, maybe I would get less of the clients that are quick in and
out because my is quite thorough and it's quite talks about consent.
And maybe it's a bit more complex or a bit more, you know, maybe
it comes across a bit more experienced rather than like big tits, big ass kind of
profile, you know. So I think like just thinking about your profile as well is a
good way to think about what clients you're getting in and if it can be tweaked a
little bit. And also what you do on cam, what you do
and what you say, you're putting that out.
So that's going to come back to you in terms of clients directly or just
what you're putting out and what you're doing is what you're going to get.
It's like an algorithm, it's like anything in life.
So yeah, just being aware of that and veering more towards the things that you want
to do and welcoming that in. Yeah, and I think
that if you just live authentically to yourself and what you want, what you like,
what you want to offer, like you said, you will attract those clients.
If you keep doing things that you're not into, this, that, it's just going to confuse
things and you're not going to know where you're at.
Whereas if you just live true to what you want, then you actually will open the space
for those clients to come to you. And you will have to let go of some clients in
the process and that's absolutely fine because you will get the ones that come to
you that want what you will offer. So yeah, never be afraid to say no to them and
let them go. I know that maybe, you know, especially in the beginning, you'll think,
oh, you know, I keep tearing all these clients away.
I'm going to have no one. Trust me, there are like thousands and thousands, maybe
even millions. Yeah, there is, there's definitely is, there's millions of clients.
So don't worry, there will be another one that comes that is much better than the
one that you've got in front of you because you'll actually gel with them.
Yeah, well, they're better for you, I should say, better for each other.
Well, thank you for the questions, everyone.
Yeah, Maria's just talking about oppression.
Yeah, I mean, I would, it's a difficult one.
I wouldn't compare different types of oppression or different types of privilege.
It's just being aware of the privilege that you have, which might play into a power
dynamic that you've got with a client. You know, it's just ethical to consider the
privileges that you have and that, that feed into a power dynamic, you know, because
that might have a lasting impact on a client or on you.
So yeah, I think that's what I was saying on that.
Nice to see your lovely face, Chloe. I just want to say something.
I was just waiting for you to finish. It's nice to see you too.
In terms of race play, as someone who has to study the broadcasting rules, because
I get told quite a lot by Aslewah, there is actually a section in the broadcasting
rules that say racism and hateful language isn't actually allowed, which I understand
if there's consent there, it's not technically hateful, but I'd also be careful because
if we're getting spot checked, they might miss the whole consent part in the beginning,
but then just see whichever party is deciding to partake in it.
And I don't know how they would see that just with the actual rules.
So, and it's a way to get out of it if you don't want to do it, because I don't do
it either. But that's what I say when someone asks me, I say, it's against the rules
on here, sorry. And then they don't normally say, oh, please, they don't really push
it, they think, okay. And then they just leave obviously, I just wanted to mention
that as well, in case anyone gets in trouble if they want them to do it, because
it does actually say in the real thing that it's not allowed.
Yeah, thank you, Terry. Thank you. Yeah, like you said, it's an easy out then, I
suppose, and just say, oh, no, it's not allowed.
You know, at least in that way. It's not you saying it.
If you don't want to say no from your, from yourself, you can just say the website
says no kind of thing. So, yeah, blame AdultWork.
I do that with most of the things that I don't want to do.
I'll get told off. Yeah, I probably was though, as well.
It's like, there's actually truth behind it.
I get put in my mouth. I kick people out sometimes and they're messaging me like,
what's happening? I'm like, I don't know.
AdultWork's just playing off, isn't it? I sometimes if
I'm lying back, and I'm bored, or I want to get rid of them, I use my toes to tear
me laptop off, but so they just move my hands.
So it looks like my laptop's there. And then I run for the week and come back and
be like, I don't know what happens. Sorry.
Yeah, I've been there before. Like, Oh, yeah, this is going great, la la.
And then like, somehow like me toes not turned off.
Oh, thank you, Chloe. Thank you for that.
Um, yes, I think that's us for today, then.
I think that's us for today. Thank you so much, everyone, for coming.
And thank you so much for your questions and for joining in.
Honestly, it's so nice to hear from you. Get your feedback and to hear about what
you're thinking. Yeah, and hope you have a great time on cam if you're going on
after this. And if not, we'll see you very soon.
Thank you everyone. See you soon. Love you all.